<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<!-- ZATON STASHES -->
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_57">
		<text>Alright, just get that cannon away from me. The stash is near the Ranger Station in Zaton, but you'll have to climb on the roof and walk along the pipes to get there. Personally, I think it's not worth it, but it's your call.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_58">
		<text>Do you like the smell of your own flesh burning? It's gonna be your new friend since I stashed that shit inside a chimney in that burning hell hole of a farm in Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_59">
		<text>I will talk, no more, please calm the fuck down! The dredge station in Zaton, there's my loot, it's right there, waiting for your greasy hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_60">
		<text>It was right under your noses the whole time. Have you ever checked out the top of Skadovsk? There, hidden on top of that old beast, is my gift to you, because you made me realize I don't need any of this shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_61">
		<text>You know that crazy bastard that lives with a mutant dog? Well, my stash is on the giant crane and you can use the anomaly on top of that old rusty ship to get there. I'm sure you could just walk right in there from the front door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_62">
		<text>A friend of mine went insane, and the next thing I see is he's running on all four like a beast. The roof of the gas station in Zaton is where my stash is. That place is full of snorks. If you see my friend there, please spare the bullets and end his miserable life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_63">
		<text>What now? You want to take everything I have, right? Rob me blind? Why would you give a fuck? But you are the boss now, the guy with a gun to my head, so get your ass to the Waste Processing Station in Zaton, it's behind a building, hidden somewhere there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_64">
		<text>Just leave me be, I've got so much to live for. I haven't even seen my daughter back home. Just take everything I have, it's in a stash behind a building in Zaton's Waste Processing Station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_65">
		<text>Listen, you could kill me right here. Splatter my brains all over, but you'd lose then. Why? Well, because I know about a stash. Oh, now you don't really want to kill me, huh? Go inside the Waste Processing Station. Figure it out from there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_66">
		<text>The Americans said that the bridge wouldn't stand forever, it seems the architect B.N. Preobrazhensky didn't make the bridge "bomb proof.” I hid my stash east of the bridge in Zaton, look for it in thick bushes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_67">
		<text>Just keep that shooter away from my face. I'll spill the beans, you won fair and square. I have to say, you are quite good at hunting people, Stalker. Head north of the Burnt Farmstead and look behind some rocks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_68">
		<text>I've been trying to save so I can finally get out of this shithole. As much as I hate Zaton, I won't last 3 hours in Yanov, not mentioning Pripyat. This stash is my last hope of ever getting out of here, man. But you take it if you have to, it is in the Ranger station in Zaton, just under a top window.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_69">
		<text>My mother was a tough broad and a good person. My father on the other hand was the worst kind of scum in the whole world. He didn't beat us with a belt, because he liked this feeling on his hands when he beat us. He was a drunk and a gambler. I lost all fear of death when I was younger because of that man. When my mom lost her job, my dad got more and more insane as the days went by. I still send them money. But you don't care, you just want my stash, right? It's on top of the huge crane in Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_70">
		<text>I know you are in a hard position here, all of us are fighting for survival. But let's be practical. Imagine if everyone was shooting and killing each other, how could you kill a chimera with a one-man team? Who would bring in more ammo? We depend on each other. Just don't shoot, and here, take my stash, it's in the tunnel close to the downed chopper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_71">
		<text> I knew this would happen, I knew some bitch like you will one day "politely" ask for my stash. So you know what I did? I made it so stealing my stash would be living fucking hell for you. You can find the stash in the Iron Forest. Search for a dark corner until you feel the surge of electricity. Feel free to die right then and there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_73">
		<text>You shit fucker. You whore bitch. I will rape your mother. I would've put a bullet to your head, if I was a bit faster. Just take the stash and die. It's in Zaton, the north west forest, behind some big rocks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_72">
		<text>Now that I think about it, maybe I have some goodies for you north of the Burnt Farmstead in Zaton. Look behind some rocks there, consider this a farewell gift, also if I might add: "please don't kill me afterwards.”</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_74">
		<text>Do you have any idea who I am? Get that fucking thing away from my eyes. If you shoot me, a hailstorm of bullets will rain on your head. Just take the stash in the hall above the tunnel in Zaton, it's not even mine, some fool begged me not to kill him and gave me its location.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_75">
		<text>I have the goodies, I have a stash, don't shoot. Stay calm, I mean you no harm. I was jittery and started shooting, the Zone does that to a person. My fault entirely. Get to the large wall in Zaton and what's mine is yours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_76">
		<text>Bushes, nobody checks in the bushes. Well, I do, and I hide shit there. You can have what I've earned through sweat and blood, it's at the very back in Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_77">
		<text>Are you a good climber? You can cash in on that stash if you carefully inspect the branches on this tree in Zaton. I hope you break your neck while climbing there but feel free to take whatever you need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_78">
		<text>My idiot brother got shot in a very similar situation because he didn't reveal our stash. I'm not doing the same mistake. Go behind a concrete pillar close to the wall in Zaton and take everything. My life is worth more than that damn stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_79">
		<text>Woah, hello there, what a pleasant way to meet a new friend. The last person I met like this is now my best friend because I showed him a great stash to raid. Go behind a concrete pillar in the dam in Zaton and see for yourself what a good friend I am.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_80">
		<text>Don't shoot, please don't shoot, I surrender, and I'm not armed. You don't want to shoot me, do you? You seem like a good enough fellow, so I will share my stash location in light of the present circumstances. It's right under the iron bridge in Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_81">
		<text>You want my stash, just don't shoot, we both lose if you shoot. I'm a mutant hunter, I make sure their numbers are in check. My stash is hidden in the bushes next to the huge boulder.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_82">
		<text>So I've become the prey, huh? I see no problem with that, and you should shoot if you have to, but I have a tasty stash for you in a container on Shevchenko in Zaton. Dunno why I'm telling you this, you can shoot me anyway, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_83">
		<text>No, shit, no. I was careless. One time I relax, this one time, and here you are, holding a gun to my head. I just hope I can remedy this situation, I offer my stash, it's located high above the ground, behind the Water Plant in good old Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_90">
		<text>Behind some metal fences in a dark corner in the basement over at Zaton I hid a sizeable amount of stuff you might be interested in. If you like it, take it, if not, I will be waiting here, you can always shoot me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_91">
		<text>I was forced to come here to this piece of shit hell. My mother said: "You will go and bring money.” But you can also take the money, my family is a bunch of assholes. It's in the last toilet in the back, in Zaton.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_92">
		<text>I've hidden something of interest to you in a dark room in the basement. In exchange for you not ending my life, I will hand over all my possession in that stash to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_93">
		<text>You look like a decent fellow, you are a good person, don't do this. My stash is hidden on the floor at the entrance, take it. Take whatever you can find, and leave me be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_94">
		<text>Please. My stash. In small house behind box in Zaton. Please, don't. Please.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_95">
		<text>In a large bush among a fuckload of trees in Zaton I hid everything I have. Take it, but keep in mind that it is literally everything I have, and you will leave me with nothing to survive in this hellhole. Beats a bullet to the head though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_96">
		<text>What you need to relax is some loot. Am I right? Do I have your attention now? There is a merc backpack in the Water Plant in Zaton that has your name on it, it used to have mine, but things change quickly in the Zone, and your gun is very persuasive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_97">
		<text>I'm sick of this, I don't want to fight anymore. To hell with this place! Take my stash, it's stored between the wall and a container, I'm through with everything here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_98">
		<text>I'm very sorry for shooting at you, it's the Zone, anyone can be the enemy. You could fix yourself up with the drugs stored in the rooms of Shevchenko in Zaton. Think of it as a gift of peace. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_99">
		<text>There is also drugs stored in the main room of Shevchenko in Zaton. Just grab them and leave me be, I have other more important things to attend to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_100">
		<text>You like to party with zombies? On the roof next to the chimney at Sawmill in Zaton you can find my stash, and a bunch of, how to put it… "half-people" to party with, have fun there, and don't forget I'm always much more valuable alive than dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_101">
		<text>On the first floor in the Ranger Station you will find a stash I was preparing to send back to my daughter in my home town. Her stepmom could sell water to a drowning man, and would make good use of that stash, but I guess you could also take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_102">
		<text>Get a sniper, at least 20 bullets, 10 if you are a sharpshooter, and clean the old Sawmill in Zaton of zombies. Then you get on top of the tractor and claim your reward, or just sneak in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_103">
		<text>Dig around the motors in the lower front of Shevchenko, you are bound to find some of my well hidden loot there, take it and watch your back, because I'm going to be your shadow for a while from now on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_104">
		<text>The gas station in Zaton has a basement with some nasty critters and also my stash that I hid well before those critters populated that place. Now, would you stop waving that cannon?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_105">
		<text>Stash, you want my stash, everyone wants my stash, but you have the gun now, so you're the one are getting my stash. It's well hidden in an elevator shaft that is locked up in Zaton. Do your worst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zat_hiding_place_106">
		<text>I left my rucksack behind the building near the teleport anomaly on the way from Zaton to Jupiter. I don't have much, so please, at least leave the photo of my wife. It's all I have left of her...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- JUPITER STASHES -->
<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_51">
		<text>How about I give you something, and you give me my life back? There is a little gift for you inside the wheel of that monstrous quarry machine in Jupiter. We have a deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_52">
		<text>Shit, I can't look at that shooter anymore. Just go take my stash, clean it out and leave me the fuck alone. Climb high on top of the Jupiter plant. What you need is outside. Are we done now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_53">
		<text>I'm done, I'm done with it all. This Zone just takes a piece of you, every single day. Take my stash, take my fucking life, this is bullshit. Behind the table in the first room is everything I've ever had, besides my life.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_54">
		<text>Listen, this is unnecessary. People get into brawls all the time here, it doesn't mean you have to blow my brains, right? Just go behind the small building, near the Jupiter Plant. The stash is outside and when you see the contents, you won't be so trigger happy next time we see each other.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_55">
		<text>You like climbing? You better be prepared for some acrobatics because my stash is well hidden high above the ground. Check the Jupiter Plant, over at the corner. Careful not to slip up, but if you do, you'd better off yourself right there. Getting your intestines ravaged by those screaming rats is a much worse experience than a quick bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_56">
		<text>Hi there, we haven't been properly introduced. I usually don't shoot at people but you looked quite menacing. As a token of my gratitude for not ending my life, go and take a look right next to the chopper in a corner in Jupiter. You will like what you find. It's right next to that metal shelf.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_57">
		<text>Next to the chopper in Jupiter you will find the reason not to rape my face with that cannon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_58">
		<text>Confession time already? Well, ok then. Forgive me father for I have sinned. I've murdered, stole and sold my friends. I'm not going to go into what I've done to my enemies. My stash is on top of the truck, in the huge hall of Jupiter. Are my sins now forgiven?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_59">
		<text>I was a dustman back home. I have absolutely no trouble digging in nasty piles of trash. If you want to find my things, go to the Train Sub Station in Jupiter. Against the wall there is a nice pile of garbage that has some goodies for you. Are we done here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_60">
		<text>The Cement factory in Jupiter, on the first floor of the building. That's what you're after, right? Unless you are just torturing me for no freaking reason, and I just gave you my valuables for no reason.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_61">
		<text>Save those bullets for the zombies in the Cement factory in Jupiter. That's where my stash is. Outside, in a concrete block. I'd shoot them bastards in the head or spine if I were you. Also if I were you, I would let me go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_62">
		<text>This is the second time, the second time today that someone is holding a gun to my head. Am I supposed to give you my other stash now? Just don't start blasting, it's in the open, under the fallen tree in good old Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_63">
		<text>This was a shitty day from the start. Got some rads in when I was on an old metal wreck, a pack of dogs chased me for 3 kilometers, and now this. One step at a time, I guess. My stash is on the roof of the shelter at the opening of the tunnel in Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_64">
		<text>What a nice shooter you have there! Did you get it from that dirtbag Owl? See, I like a man with a taste in guns. Go get my stash, it's inside the tunnel in Jupiter, look for some concrete mess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_65">
		<text>The time has come, huh? I can't believe I've made it so far. But maybe there is a fleeting chance that I'd trade my freedom for a stash? Go outside and above the tunnel in Jupiter. Then think about it, I will be right here waiting patiently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_66">
		<text>You whore bitch. My weapon got stuck, if it hadn't, it would've been you on your knees. Take my shit, it's at helipads. Close to the wall, in Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_67">
		<text>In Jupiter, go where a concrete pillar close to helipads is, and you will feel much better for letting me live. Or you could just waste me here and take my stash, but then maybe karma will bite you in the ass and a controller will fry your brain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_68">
		<text>I haven't seen you around before, are you new here? You seem to be quite capable with your tools. Maybe we'll come to an agreement? I give you my stash, you let me go. How does that sound? Alright, it is camouflaged in some bushes in the northern quarry, Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_69">
		<text>I've heard that to west of the Jupiter plant, at the very back behind a brick building there is a stash full of the good stuff. How about you do me a favor now and let me go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_70">
		<text>Hey, your gun safety is on! Look... No? Well, at least I tried. Seems to work in movies and computer games. Ok, I surrender and you can take my stash that is in the Jupiter plant. On the top floor, in the staircase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_71">
		<text>Ready to visit the scientists? Go get my stash in the Scientist bunker, in the southern corner and bring it back to me, then I will decide if I'll let you live.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_88">
		<text>Did you know that many interesting things happen under the bridge? I've found so many useful things getting washed up from the river. Once I found some denim, perfectly fine after a bit of boiling. Go to the eastern corner in Jupiter, I hid my stash under that bridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_89">
		<text>I came here with my brother, we got separated when he joined Duty while I was a dedicated Freedom member. Before departing he told me that if push comes to shove, he stashed some goodies under the bridge, in the western corner in Jupiter. It's yours now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_90">
		<text>How about I buy out my life in exchange for a stash? Go visit the Jupiter Plant, and walk along to the highest building there. It's near a tree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_91">
		<text>No, no, wait. I have things you might use. Don't shoot me, just go get my stash in Jupiter Plant. Outside, in the shed. No reason for more violence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_92">
		<text>I couldn't see it was you, I would never shoot you. We wouldn't be in this situation if I knew it was you. I've seen you around and you look like a decent guy. As an apology, take my stash. It's in the Jupiter Plant. Top floor, near the staircase.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_93">
		<text>Where there is radiation, no fool would go. Right? Well, not unless you've got 2 bottles of vodka and a strong will. Just go inside the bus in the Jupiter Plant. You'll run into some radiation and eventually come across my stash. I would advise against eating anything you find there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_94">
		<text>Sneak into the bandit base, or just go in blazing. Get up on the top floor. The sleeping room is exactly where my stash is. And now you'll casually let me go, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_72">
		<text>Hey friend, you won't shoot when I'm so friendly to you, right? Here, take my stash in Kopatchy Village. It's inside the ruins of grey brick. It's completely safe there, friend, you don't even need to take guns, not even anti-rads or vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_73">
		<text>Pull the fucking trigger, just finish me already because I have nothing for you except my measly stash in Kopatchy Village. Inside the ruins of a wooden house. But I've heard that the radiation is quite high there, so you better be prepared for puking your guts out for a month.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_74">
		<text>If you don't pull the trigger, I will the next time I see you. I won't hesitate like you... Ah, you actually want my stash, right? It's in Kopatchy Village. Inside the ruins of grey concrete. Now piss off or let's get this over with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_75">
		<text>You seem like a tough bastard, capable, quick to draw the gun, I bet you would rather shoot the mutant that won't fucking leave the place where I stashed my things than my beautiful face. Am I right? Eastern tunnel in Jupiter. In a small room. Bring many bullets.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_76">
		<text>Ever since I was a kid, I had this unhealthy obsession with trains. Back then they ran on gasoline and were filthy as fuck. I used to hang around trains all the time and the pollution there was awful. Now I need money for cancer treatment in Germany. But you don't give three fucks about that, right? Just go to the eastern tunnel. On top of the train. I can't go there anymore, because some mutant has its lair there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_77">
		<text>The most sophisticated anti-aircraft system ever devised. That's what they called the Volkov AA Complex. That was naturally all bullshit propaganda. You can gather some loot there since I stashed some of my things in the large brick building.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_78">
		<text>I've heard that in Jupiter there is some pretty good loot for the taking inside the Container Warehouse. I gave you what you wanted, so let me go. Please? I have children, two boys and a girl, they don't know I'm here. Check inside the storeroom full of wooden boxes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_79">
		<text>How about I buy off the bullet you wanted to shoot me with? I've got some good things stashed in the Container Warehouse. Between some large containers. You could certainly handle that. So can I have that bullet? If you fire it, it will be worthless to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_80">
		<text>I've never had to kneel before another person till this moment. My father taught me to show respect, and I would be respected. Shooting people isn't very respectful though. To mend our situation here, how about you take my stash? It's in the Container Warehouse. On the roof of the building in the back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_84">
		<text>Go west of the Container Warehouse in Jupiter, and you will find what you need underwater behind huge rocks. I have nothing else to give you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_85">
		<text>I was once in a similar situation. I told this old bandit that I didn't have anything. I did not lie, and I won't lie to you now. I keep my stuff in a large dead bush west of the Container Warehouse. Next time he captures me, I'll have nothing for him once again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_86">
		<text>Tall grass is an excellent camouflage. You could stay there for months hidden from mutants, bandits and mercs. I stashed some of my stuff in high grass next to a tree, on top of the hill. Try to find it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jup_hiding_place_87">
		<text>Keep your finger off the trigger, you can't use me if I'm dead. Take my stash, it's next to the giant old tree in the bushes.</text>
	</string>

	<!-- PRIPYAT STASHES -->
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_32">
		<text>I've got nothing, man, I'm cool now, I won't shoot. I heard about a stash in Pripyat, behind the storage houses in the backyard of Laundromat. But that's all I got, man. Can I leave now, is that it?</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_33">
		<text>Old Stalkers talk about Pripyat like it's the Devil's own penthouse. I would never take one step there, but if you happen to get there, there's a stash near the Laundromat hidden in some bushes. This is my gift to you, so we can part as friends, and so you don't have to dirty your hands.</text>
	</string>
			<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_34">
		<text>That ghost town Pripyat sure holds a lot of secrets. I happened to overhear one of them when some old bandits were fighting over the last vodka bottle. Then they got mauled by a chimera, and I took flight immediately. I heard them say that the stash is by the steps, next to a staircase leading down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_35">
		<text>Many buildings in Pipyat have been completely cleaned out by now, whatever they hid before is long gone now. Remember, Pripyat brings only death and suffering. Still, there's this one stash I know about, it's over there in these dried out bushes near red brick buildings.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_36">
		<text>Pripyat used to be a bustling city, filled with life and energy. Today? It's the opposite. There were a few Stalkers that managed to survive there for a while and hid some stashes during their stay. Go to the terrace of the Riverport and take what they left there in exchange for my liberty.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_37">
		<text>I intercepted a transmission back when I fiddled with DIY radio, it was strangely from Pripyat. It was sent by a dying Stalker who wanted anyone who was listening to take his stash. Probably because he almost breathed his last. You could take it, just go to the top floor of the Apartment Complex. Climb the stairs, it's right there.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_38">
		<text>I have nothing of worth for you. But I do know about a stash in the back room at the gas station in Pripyat, although who the hell would be as suicidal as to go there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_39">
		<text>Darkness in Pripyat is something else. It breaks your mind, plays tricks on you. Things begin to move on their own, you see monsters that don't even exist! But if you are bold enough, check behind some boxes in a darkroom over at Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_40">
		<text>I found a big bag full of some notes, I grabbed a few of them and ran as fast as I could since I had a bunch of fleshes on my back. Most notes were just crazy mumblings, but a stash was clearly marked on one of them. It's on top of crates in good old Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_41">
		<text>Pripyat is a deadly desert and for a good reason. It changes you. People come back from there like they've seen the other side of the abyss. But if fortune doesn't smile on you and you need to go there, go to the back of the Apartment complex and get the stash that's hidden there.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_42">
		<text>Well, I gave my best shot. Pull the trigger or listen to me carefully. I know about a stash in Pripyat. Visit the Apartment complex. Go to the top floor. Climb some stairs. It's there, don't ask how I came to know this.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_43">
		<text>Fuck no, not today, please. I was supposed to fucking leave tomorrow. I greased the military at the barricades and everything. Could you let me be in exchange for a stash location? Go to the Apartment complex in Pripyat. Back room. We ok now?</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_44">
		<text>Please don't do anything to me, I beg of you, don't shoot! I was a good guy, things forced me to do this, it's not my fault. Here, go to the Apartment complex in Pripyat, look in the toilets. I overheard some Stalkers joking that nobody in their right mind would ever look there for a stash.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_45">
		<text>I surrender, take everything, I won't move. I also overheard some robocop guy talk about the time when he was in Pripyat, he hid a stash in the lobby of the Prometheus Movie Theater.</text>
	</string>
			<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_46">
		<text>Stop, I'm unarmed. Don't do this, please. I've heard about this stash, in the hallway close to Prometheus Movie Theater. I know it's in Pripyat, so this information isn't worth much to you, but please don't kill me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_47">
		<text>You like being in this position now, huh? I'm your bitch now? Well, the "bitch" is worth more to you alive than dead. I know about a stash, it's supposed to hold tons of good stuff, but it's in Pripyat, under the iron elephant. Good luck.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_48">
		<text>Keep that gun away from my head. Get to the bookstore in Pripyat. Top floor holds some nice presents for you. Now leave me be.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_49">
		<text>How about you head to Pripyat now instead of killing another good person for no good reason? There is a stash next to the fireplace inside Prometheus Movie Theater. It's completely safe there, you don't even have to carry any weapons or anything.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_50">
		<text>This is not what I had in mind when I came into this slum pit. After this, I'm going back, fuck curiosity. Go to Pripyat and high above the campsite inside Prometheus Movie Theater you will find a little something as a token of gratitude for letting me go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_51">
		<text>No, please, no! They say don't go to Pripyat, so don't. But if you want my stash, you have to. Take a look under the stairs in the Prometheus Movie Theater. Now I have to go, I have urgent matters to attend to.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_52">
		<text>Pripyat holds many secrets, but not many people know that it also holds many stashes from way back. Check the small room in the kindergarten. If you see children, start running and don't look back until you hit the ocean.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_53">
		<text>Stop that shit right now, get that shooter off my face. Go to the roof of the kindergarten in Pripyat, I'm never gonna go there anyway, this place stinks.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_54">
		<text>There is a treasure hidden inside the Yubileiny Service Center in Pripyat. Look for a stash there, and let me go my own way.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_55">
		<text>Toilets, nobody checks the toilets. Go to the Yubileiny Service Center and prepare to get your hands dirty. If you survive the trip. Pripyat is where you go if you've got a death wish.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_56">
		<text>They told me never to go to Pripyat. Something evil is there, and slowly devours the souls of curious visitors. Although someone did go there, and stashed his loot. It's in the Apartment block, behind a stock door leading down.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_57">
		<text>The French came up with the "Art of Displacement,” parkour they called it. Came out of military obstacle course. If you'd like to get your hands on some good loot, and you aren't afraid to look deep inside a hell full of unfathomable terrors, go to Pripyat, the stash is on the roof of a derelict building.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_58">
		<text>I'm sure you already know the horrors of Pripyat, you might wanna know the underground is far worse. If you aren't afraid, go deep underground, even below the basement and you will get yourself some nice loot to keep you going for a while longer.</text>
	</string>
		<string id="st_pri_hiding_place_59">
		<text>Pripyat is hell, everyone knows that, but some people did manage to survive there, if only for a short while. One of them hid a stash there, it's cleverly hidden right under the roof. That should change your mind about blowing my brains out, right?</text>
	</string>
</string_table> 